K. PRASHANT

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Creative **Consultant Specialist**, skillful in executing effective operating rhythms and management systems structures. Offering **5 years of expertise** in analyzing, articulating and solving various customer related problems thus, showcasing both technical and interpersonal aptitude to maintain the integrity of the organization.

WORK HISTORY

Consultant Specialist, 04/2021 - Current

HSBC Technology, Pune, India

- Contributed to valuable growth by managing and maintaining business relationships with several stakeholders and partners.
- Boosted customer experiences by delivering and collaborating across various teams to design and execute migration of Microservices to Kubernetes On-Premise.
- Own analyst responses to showcase POD's lead role and demonstrate prominent solutions to enhance the conversions of Java Applications into Kubernetes Containers.
- Developed an effective improvement plan to prioritize JIRA tasks and manage sprints to ensure consistency within a workflow.
- Enhance CR Automation Tool by seamless integrations with JIRA, Confluence & Chat Applications (Slack + Symphony) i.e. now used widely across the organization to meet faster deliveries.

Senior Software Engineer, 04/2019 - 03/2021

HSBC Technology, Pune, India

- Developed microservices in core JAVA that are now significantly hosted in HSBC's ICP.
- Introduced agile methodologies and development practices to improve ELK monitoring platform and optimized the APM standards, thus reducing operational costs and future risks.
- Worked closely with several development teams and infrastructure specialists to deliver **high availability solutions** for critical applications.
- Built real time position management service for **Bloomberg** trades that included designs for database storage structure,

- **?** Pune, India 411014
- 7549114328
 - kpofficial2402@gmail.com

SKILLS

- Core Java 7/8/11
- Shell Scripting
- Puppet
- Ansible
- Vert.X
- MongoDB
- ELK Stack
- Kubernetes
- Docker
- Rundeck
- Micro-Services
- Web-Services
- JMS
- Python
- gRPC

customized sequential processing, and neglected the discrepancy of incorrect position calculations.

- Explored Vert.X toolkit to develop REST Web Services for the trade store.
- Improved & initiated the **DevOps Tooling** in the organization by contributing towards the development of CR Automation Tool to ensure **constructive compliance** throughout the processes.
- Designed & developed prototype of the analytics tool using
 Data science, to measure customer segmentation, and hence propose personalized offers.

Software Engineer, 08/2016 - 03/2019

HSBC Technology, Pune, India

- Reviewed project specifications and designed a structural POC Plan; (now a fully funded project) for building a scalable Front Office Datastore of Fixed Income & BSM Business.
- Visited **HSBC's HQ, (London, UK)** to deliver pitch to traders & illustrate usage of **Common Data Model** for **Data Store**.
- Served as a SME on creating the Future State Architecture that focused on several legacy systems as a scope of meeting the product goal.
- Orchestrated the storage of data in **MongoDB**, & incorporated effective parameters to maintain the formation of core framework.
- Identified and framed different methodologies to write SQL stored procedure subroutines for risk calculations.
- Automated the time consumption design of Control M jobs using Python thus, modularized its performance solutions.

EDUCATION

Bachelors of Engineering, 04/2016

National Institute of Technology - Jamshedpur *GPA: 8.86(10)*

ACCOMPLISHMENTS

- Awarded Technologist of the Quarter, 2020.
- Listed in TOP 20 Developers HSBC Technology, 2020.
- Visited HSBC HQ (Onsite) Sept Oct, 2019.
- Achieved Best Project of the Year HSBC Technology, 2019.